Alright guys, next up we'll be discussing our comprehensive client onboarding here
at Jamie Fitness. So, why is onboarding crucial?
Just like you're being onboarded right now as a trainer,
onboarding clients establishes a strong foundation for long term success.
It sets them up for success. It helps them understand and utilize our tools
and resources a lot faster than just assuming they'll catch on over
time. It builds rapport with you and it sets clear
expectations of the level we're at and ensures clients
feel supported and confident from the very beginning.
So, here's an overview. Overview of our three-week onboarding process.
Week one is about nutrition. Tracking their meals,
specifically using the meal guide created in the Jamie Fitness app that we covered
at the very start of these modules.
The goal, effective meal tracking to get them aware of their food.
Understanding how their eating actually is.
Week two is physical activity awareness focus.
We're setting them up to track their steps.
And this is just to get more movement day-to-day to help them burn more
calories. And lastly,
week three, self-dependence and training.
We're encouraging them to come to the gym by themselves.
Which can be a big step for some of them. This helps to build
confidence in coming to the gym by themselves.
Week four and beyond is about long-term habits.
Now that we know a lot about what they're good at,
what they're not good at, what they're struggling with,
what they're successful with. We can give them hyper-specific habits.
That's going to help them achieve long-term results.
So we focus on movement,
mindset and nutrition habits.
So week one,
quick overview. We're introducing the clients to the meal guide creator in Jamie Fitness.
We've got to make sure their account is set up. We've got to demonstrate
how it works. we're showing them how the meal planning and the tracking and
the shopping list feature works too. And we're setting up their habit tracking
for the daily meal logging.
The follow up is asking questions in the sessions afterwards.
Week two is physical activity awareness, educating clients on the importance of daily meal
planning. We're setting up their step tracker in the app
or their phone. We're setting a goal of hitting 10k steps a day.
We are implementing our habit tracking for them to track their daily steps
and we're guiding them on how to use the app to track their steps.
And again, we're asking them a question.
We're
going to set a specific day for them to do their independent training session.
And of course we're going to implement habit tracking for that solo session.
And we're going to follow up with questions. four and beyond,
we're going to establish long term habits. Three habits from the categories mindset,
movement and nutrition. We're going to review how they went with those three week
habits at the start. We're going to select new habits from something called the
habit catalog and questionnaire. And we're going to set them up for the next
nine weeks to equal 12 weeks in total.
That's a very quick overview on our onboarding process,
now we're going to deep dive into each week one by one.